



# Aldo Testino

O Home: Via Degli Orti 3, 70033, Corato, Italy

**Email:** aldotestino4@gmail.com **Phone:** (+39) 3298776330

★ Website: aldotestino.vercel.app/

in Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/aldo-testino-56486a244/

GitHub: github.com/aldotestino

Date of birth: 30/01/2001 Nationality: Italian

## **ABOUT ME**

After completing my bachelor's degree in Computer and Automation Engineering with an experimental thesis in collaboration with the startup Leaf s.r.l., I decided to further my education by pursuing a master's degree in Computer Engineering with a specialization in the Cyberphysical Systems curriculum.

My academic and professional path has instilled in me a passion for researching and developing advanced computer systems, particularly in the field of cyberphysical systems. I am always on the lookout for new challenges and opportunities to contribute to technology's evolution.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAIN-**ING

## [ 09/2014 – 06/2019 ] **Diploma Scientifico**

Liceo Scientifico e Linguistico O.Tedone liceotedone.edu.it

City: Ruvo di Puglia | Country: Italy | Field(s) of study: Scienze applicate | Final

**grade:** 100

[ 09/2019 - 07/2022 ] **Laurea Triennale** 

Politecnico di Bari poliba.it

City: Bari | Country: Italy | Field(s) of study: Ingegneria Informatica e dell'Automazione | Final grade: 110 Cum Laude | Thesis: Sviluppo di un sistema integrato per la gestione, il monitoraggio ed il tracciamento di coltivazioni di nuova generazione attraverso dispositivi IoT in tema di agricoltura 4.0

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## [ 14/10/2024 - Current ] Solution Designer PaaS/SaaS Design

Olivetti

**City:** Bari | **Country:** Italy

## [01/06/2022 - Current] Application developer

Leaf s.r.l.

City: Bari | Country: Italy

- full stack development
- technologies: React, Node, Fastify, Prisma, MongoDB

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Fontanelle**

#### Description

Worked on this Web App for almost two months. It allows users to find the nearest public fountain, add new ones, vote and report their problems.

#### **Technologies**

Go, React, PostgreSQL, Mapbox, Google Cloud, Docker, Nginx

Link: github.com/aldotestino/fontanelle

#### **Instant Messaging**

## **Description**

This is one of my first projects. It is a simple instant messaging app that allows users to send messages to each other.

## **Technologies**

Node.Js, React, PostgreSQL, Prisma, GraphQL, Docker

Link: github.com/aldotestino/instant-messaging

#### **Vctmang**

## **Description**

This is a project work for the course of Fondamenti Web at Politecnico di Bari. It is a website for a fictional fast food company.

## **Technologies**

Node.js, Express.js, React, MongoDB, REST Api, Socket.io, Docker

Link: github.com/aldotestino/vcetmang

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Italian

Other language(s):

#### **English**

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

## **My Digital Skills**

#### **Programming Languages**

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | Python | Go | Java | SQL

#### **Databases**

PostgreSQL | MongoDB

## Frameworks, libraries and environments

fastify.js | Node.js | React/Next.js | Pytorch (beginner level) | Prisma (ORM) | Expre ss.js | Go-Gin | GORM | REST e GraphQL API

#### **Tools**

Git | Docker | Figma